Guide to the John Elari Photographic Slide Collection 1965-1999 PR 285
New-York Historical Society
John Elari photographic slide collection
1965-1999
New-York Historical Society
Elari, John, 1943-
PR 285
0.4 Linear feet (1 box)
This collection consists of 1,000 photographic slides taken by New York City resident John Elari (1943- ). The collection spans the period from 1965-1999 and is composed of images of New York City and its inhabitants.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials in this collection may be stored offsite. For more information on making arrangements to consult them, please visit www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of John Elari, 2016.
Biographical Note
John Elari was born in Brooklyn, NY on 6 April 1943. He developed an interest in photography while spending the summer of 1964 traveling in Europe. Elari completed a degree in interior design at the Paier School of Art in Hamden, CT in 1965, and then moved back to New York City. He worked as an interior designer, and then as a florist from 1974-2000, all the while honing his photography skills. Elari's photographs document the cityscape and street life of New York City from 1965-1999.
Scope and Contents
The John Elari Photographic Slide Collection consists of 1,000 color slides of New York City, mainly Manhattan, taken between 1965 and 1999. The collection is arranged by the subject of the photograph, as originally identified and organized by the photographer. These subjects include Bridges, Buildings, Events, Monuments and Statues, Neighborhoods, Night Scenes, Parks and Gardens, People, Skylines and Cityscapes, and Transportation. Labels on the slide sheets, as well as any titles and dates on the slides, were provided by the photographer.
Color photographs.; Slides (photographs).; Bridges -- New York (State) -- New York -- Photographs.; Buildings -- New York (State) -- New York -- Photographs.; Monuments -- New York (State) -- New York -- Photographs.; Neighborhoods -- New York (State) -- New York -- Photographs.; Parks -- New York (State) -- New York -- Photographs.; Street life -- New York (State) -- New York -- Photographs.; Transportation -- New York (State) -- New York -- Photographs.; Manhattan (New York, N.Y.) -- Photographs.; New York (N.Y.) -- Photographs.
- Bridges, 1979-1999 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents Note
  Images of NYC bridges, including the Brooklyn Bridge and Williamsburg Bridge.
- Buildings, 1977-1992 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Photos of Broadway theaters, Chrysler Building, Empire State Building, Pan Am Building, Rockefeller Center, Trump Tower, and the World Trade Center (Twin Towers).
- Events, 1971-1999 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Images of the Macy's Thanksgiving Day parade, the Bicentennial Celebration, Christmas displays, and the Easter parade.
- Exceptionals, 1965-1999 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  These are the images that the photographer, John Elari, considered "the best of the lot." He labeled these "the exceptionals." The subject matter of the slides is consistent with the other slide sheets.
- Monuments and Statues, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Images of the Statue of Liberty.
- Neighborhoods, 1991, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Views of Chinatown, Times Square, and the Financial District.
- Night Scenes, 1965-1992 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Photographs that capture New York City after dark, including views of Lincoln Center, Park Ave, and the Upper West Side.
- Parks and Gardens, 1977-1996 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Images of the Brooklyn Botanic Gardens, Central Park, Hudson River Park. Also includes images of people playing volleyball, and snow scenes.
- People, 1969-1999 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Includes images of people in parks, street performers, musicians, street vendors, chess players, children, elderly people, and homeless people.
- Skylines and Cityscapes, 1970-1999 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Views of Manhattan from different vantage points. Includes images of cars and street traffic, digital neon signs, and street views.
- Transportation, 1990-1998; PR 285 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Images of buses, subway stations and trains, and the Staten Island Ferry.